PHIL BOURASSA

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JAVASCRIPT ES6

REACT JS GIT/GITHUB

JQUERY GULP

HTML5 VS CODE

CSS3 COMMAND LINE

SASS API

FIREBASE BILINGUAL (ER/FR)

EDUCATION

HAKERYOU, 2018

IMMERSIVE FRONT-END BOOTCAMP

PART-TIME WEB DEVELOPMENT

PART-TIME JAVASCRIPT AND JQUERY

MCMASTER UNIVERSITY, 1999-2004

BACHELOR OF MANUFACTURING

ENGINEERING AND SOCIETY

CONTACT

647 829 4112
BOURASSA.PHIL@GMAIL.COM

@PHILBOURASSA_
LINKEDIN.COM/IN/PHILBOU

TORONTO, ON

PROFILE

I am a web developer, who is passionate about creative problem-solving and delivering quality product - a passion which began during my experience as a QA Analyst. I run a dance school, enthusiastic about community organizing and teaching new skills. I enjoy creative challenges and am excited by opportunities to experiment and think outside the box.

EXPERIENCE

TD QUALITY ASSURANCE ANALYST, 2012 - 2018

- Proficient in HP Quality Center, IBM Host on Demand and JIRA, implementing Waterfall and Agile methodologies to meet business and systems requirements
- Coordinating with testers, product owners and developers to deliver 6+ projects annually

BUSINESS PARTNER, 2014-PRESENT

 Manage a group of 16 teachers and administrative staff

VOLUNTEER AT LADIES LEARNING CODE, 2018

 Mentored a JavaScript for Beginners workshop, hosting 25+ students

SELECTED WORKS

Superhero Battle React, Firebase, API

Simify

JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, APIs

View live at: www.philbourassa.ca